Arun Kumar K

Data Scientist

3E, Sukriti, Thoraipakkam, Chennai, Tamil Nadu 7502710750 kumar.arun24@outlook.com

Data Scientist with 8.5+ years of Experience in data-driven technologies and products, serving clients across Communications, the Internet, and Hospitality Industries. Proficient at collecting, analyzing, Interpreting large datasets, and developing new models to improve business operations

WORK HISTORY

Software Engineer II(NLP) —Bank of America, Chennai

AUG 2022 - present

- Built a conversation AI Chatbot using the RASA open source to assist the user queries across different banking platform
- Improved the Objects Recognition by using the knowledge base actions.
- Gathered Insights to Improve the intent detections and accuracy of the responses using the CDD Processes.
- Facilitating Change Management for the Model Changes and Custom Components changes and Configurations

AI/ML Engineer —Virtusa, Chennai

SEP 2021 - Aug 2022

- Developed an conversational AI Chatbot to automate Day to Day Banking Activities, and Improved Customer Experience.
- Improved the User Engagement metrics by adopting the different techniques like Contextual memory, Multi Intent Detections etc.

Data Scientist — Tata Consultancy Services, Chennai

Mayr 2016 - Aug 2021

- Built Classification Models to Personalize the Guest Experiences in Hospitality Industry
- Collected, analyzed and interpreted the raw data from the Oracle Databases ensuring data quality and integrity
- Build Predictive Models using Multiple Machine Learning tools to predict the possibility of Airline delays

<u>Data Scientist</u> — Tata Consultancy Services, Bangalore

May 2015 - Mar 2016

• Provided the Techno-Functional implementation for the Financial Process and Service Contract Process for LinkedIn

SKILLS

- Machine Learning
- Natural language Processing (NLP)
- Statistical Analysis
- Python
- SQL

Languages English, Tamil

Date of Birth: 24/Aug/1994 Gender: Male

Education:

M.Kumarasamy College of Engineering, Tamil Nadu -B.E (EIE) MAY 2011 -MAY 2015